The greatest gladiator match in the history of the world.
Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice is a action,
adventure, fantasy film directed by Zack Snyder.
Fearing the actions of a god-like Super Hero left unchecked, Gotham City’s own formidable, forceful vigilante takes on
Metropolis’s most revered, modern-day savior, while the world wrestles with what sort of hero it really needs.
And with Batman and Superman at war with one another, a new threat quickly
arises, putting mankind in greater danger than it’s ever known before.
Bruce Wayne / Batman, played by Ben Affleck.
Clark Kent / Superman, played by Henry Cavill.
Lex Luthor, played by Jesse Eisenberg.
Diana Prince / Wonder Woman, played by Gal Gadot.
Lois, played by Amy Adams.
Martha Kent, played by Diane Lane.
Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice is a 2016 American superhero film
based on the DC Comics characters Batman and Superman.
Directed by Zack Snyder and written by Chris Terrio and David S.
Goyer, it is a follow-up to Man of Steel (2013) and the
second film in the DC Extended Universe (DCEU).
The film stars Ben Affleck as Batman and Henry Cavill as Superman, alongside an ensemble cast including Amy
Adams, Jesse Eisenberg, Diane Lane, Laurence Fishburne, Jeremy Irons, Holly Hunter, and Gal Gadot.
Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice is the first live-action film to feature Batman and Superman
together, as well as the first live-action cinematic portrayal of Wonder Woman.
In the film, criminal mastermind Lex Luthor manipulates Batman into a preemptive
battle with Superman, whom Luthor is obsessed with destroying.
The film was announced at the 2013 San Diego
Comic-Con after the release of Man of Steel.
Snyder stated that the film would take inspiration from the Batman comic book series The Dark
Knight Returns by Frank Miller, but clarified that it would follow an original premise.
The incarnation of Batman in the film is different from the character's previous portrayal by
Christian Bale in The Dark Knight trilogy, serving as a cinematic reboot of the character.
The film is also inspired by narrative elements from the
Superman comic book series The Death of Superman.
Pre-production began at East Los Angeles College in October 2013, and
principal photography started in May 2014 in Detroit.
Additional filming also took place in Illinois and
New Mexico, concluding in December.
Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice premiered at the Auditorio Nacional in Mexico City on March
19, 2016, and was released in the United States on March 25, by Warner Bros.
It grossed $874 million worldwide against a budget of $250–325 million, becoming the seventh-highest-grossing film of
2016, while also having the biggest opening weekend for a superhero film at the time of its release.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
A director's cut, dubbed the "Ultimate Edition", features 31 minutes of
additional footage and was released to home media formats later in 2016.
A follow-up, titled Justice League, was released on November 17, 2017.
The film explores themes of superhero, based on
comic, revenge, vigilante, super power.